Finding Aid for John Teachout phonograph record collection, 1950-1964 and undated
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
John Teachout phonograph record collection 1950-1964, undated
Teachout, John.
67 phonograph records (in 3 boxes)
2010076 Aa 2
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was the gift of Alice Teachout (donor no. 10283 ) and came to the library in 2009.
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research.
John Teachout was an Ann Arbor, Michigan record producer. The name of his company was Idiom Recording.
The John Teachout collection consists of phonograph records produced by his Idiom Recording Company. Several of the records are of local Ann Arbor or University of Michigan performances. In addition to music, some of the records are of dramatic readings. A few of the identifications are uncertain as they were taken from hand-written labels.
Subjects: Sound Recordings
Idiom Recording Company.; Teachout, John.
Contributors:
Warren, Austin, 1899-1986.
Genre Terms:
Sound recordings.; Phonograph records.
- Phonograph Records, 33 1/3 unless otherwise indicated
  - Side A: Modern Jazz; Side B: Modern (Box 1)
  - Side A: Concert Band March; Side B: Concert Band (Box 1)
  - Side A: Piano Concert; Side B: Leah Sadowsky recital, University of Michigan Broadcast Service (Box 1)
  - Side A: The Congo, The Santa Fe Trail, Vachel Lindsay; Side B: Introduction by John A. Nist reading of Edgar Allen Poe poetry, The Raven, Annabel Lee, The Bells (Box 1)
  - Side A: Folk Songs of Brazil; Side B: My Encores (Bidú Sayão) (Box 1)
  - Side A: Les circeurs de souliers de Broadway, Si vous aimiez, Terre Terre, Maladie d'amour, Guitar, Ma Mie (78 rpm); Side B: Django (33 1/3 rpm) (Box 1)
  - Side A: Clopin-Clopant, Verlaine: Las Sang lots longs des violins, Que reste-t-il de nos amours, Les enfants qui s'aiment, Les Feuilles Mortes, A Paris (Box 1)
  - Side A: Il fait des..., D'est le retour des saisons, N'y peuse pas trop, Mon Bateau, La mes, Ma rue et moi (Box 1)
  - Side A: Seul depuis toujours, Mes jeunes annees, Douce France, Retour a Paris, Elle a ..., Parce que ca me donne du courage (Box 1)
  - Side A: Eerie Sounds! Almost background music (Box 1)
  - Foreign Language Choral Music Side A: Violin, Chorus, Piano & Chorus; Side B: Violin Music, Mandolin & Solo Singer plus Chorus, Piano-Voice, Chorus, Chorus Bass Voice (Box 1)
  - Side A: Petrouchka, University Symphony, Wayne Dunlap 1952 (Box 1)
  - Both Sides: Violin and Piano Recital Music (Unidentified) (Box 1)
  - Side A: Our Hour 02/13/1957 (Box 1)
  - Side A: Fourteen Poems; Side B: Selections from The Temple (Box 1)
  - Side A: The Pines of Rome; Side B: Two Nocturnes (Box 1)
  - Both Sides: The Poetry of John Donne Volume 1 (Box 1)
  - Both Sides: The Poetry of John Donne Volume 2 (Box 1)
  - Side A: Austin Warren reading Edgar Allan Poe; Side B: Austin Warren reading Walt Whitman (Box 1)
  - Side A: Austin Warren 1950 Humorous Verse; Side B: Edward Reeves parodies (Box 1)
  - Side A: French; Side B: George Brassens (from a tape) (Box 1)
  - Pioneer High School, The King and I (Box 2)
  - Side A: John Mist reading Shakespeare; Side B: John Nist reading Kipling (Box 2)
  - Side A: Austin Warren reading John Milton; Side B: Austin Warren reading Alexander Pope (Box 2)
  - Side A: Symphony #1, Gordon Sherwood (Box 2)
  - Side A: U of M 1958 I.F.C. Sing; Side B: U of M 1958 I.F.C. Sing; includes Fraternity All Stars in the Lord's Prayer (Box 2)
  - Both Sides: Pioneer High School, Ye Bloody Rebels (Box 2)
  - Side A: Youth for Understanding (Box 2)
  - Both Sides: Crusk Cross-Age Helping Program (Box 2)
  - Side A: Hospital insurance for the aged under social security prepared by Michigan Democratic Party, national legislation action program (operation support); Side B: Discussion of current issues by U.S. Senator Philip A. Hart and Congressman-at-large Neil Staebler at Wayne County's Democratic Women's Day January 25, 1964 (Box 2)
  - 1955 Interfraternity Council Sing; Side A: Theta Chi, Lambda Chi Alpha, Sigma Phi Epsilon, Phi Gamma Delta, Theta Chi, Sigma Chi; Side B: Chi Psi, Beta Theta Pi, Delta Tau Delta, Phi Kappa Tau (Box 2)
  - University of Michigan Symphony Band 1952-53 Side A; Persichetti: Divertimento for Band; Side B: Jacob: Music for a Festival (Box 2)
  - 1954 Interfraternity Council Sing; Side A: Sigma Phi Epsilon, Sigma Nu, Phi Gamma Delta, Phi Delta Theta, Theta Xi, Lambda Chi Alpha; Side B: Delta Tau Delta, Beta Theta Pi, Alpha Phi Alpha, Acacia, Award Ceremony (Box 2)
  - Both Sides: Saline High School Band (Box 2)
  - Both Sides: Crusk Cross-Age Helping Program (Box 2)
  - Side B: Reference Recording, Panel Discussion (Box 2)
  - Side A: Reference Recording, Hospital Insurance Program (Box 2)
  - Side A: Reference Recording, Selections from the Messiah (Box 2)
  - Side B: Reference Recording, Selections from the Messiah (Box 2)
  - Side A: Ruthbone, Girl Like You-1st Part, 3 of Biggest; Side B: Finale (Box 2)
  - Side A: The Girl in the Grey Flannel Toga (Box 2)
  - Both Sides: First Methodist Church, Retirement Sermon of Rev. Rial Simons (Box 2)
  - Side A: Crystalaire Camp for Girls, Crystalaire Songs (Box 2)
  - Side B: Ypsilanti High School Band Program (Box 2)
  - Side A: Ypsilanti High School Band Program (Box 2)
  - Side A: Friars Song, Froggy Bottom, Rights for Wives; Side B: College M..., Til the Dawn (Box 2)
  - Side A: Ted Lewis Collection from Havens (Box 2)
  - Side A: Pete Daly (Box 2)
  - Side A: 1951 I.F.C. Sing, Chi Psi, Persian Kitten (78 rpm); Side B: 1951 I.F.C. Sing, Blue Room (Box 3)
  - Side A: Minnie the Mermaid Medley, Chicago Medley, Carolina in the Morning (Box 3)
  - Both Sides: Concordia College Record (Box 3)
  - Both Sides: Youth for Understanding Program (Box 3)
  - Side A: Youth for Understanding Chorale, Every Time I Feel the Spirit; B: Youth for Understanding Chorale, Ezekiel Saw De Wheel (Box 3)
  - Side A: Bright Star Jubilee Singers (Box 3)
  - Both Sides: Youth for Understanding Program (Box 3)
  - Both Sides: Sigma Sings for the 50th Anniversary (Box 3)
  - Side A: Ain't misbehaving; Side B: Buzz Me (Box 3)
  - Both Sides: Bright Star Jubilee Singers (include Climbin' the rough side of the mountain; Will you be waitin' at the Pearly Gates, and others (Box 3)
  - Side A: J-Hop, Bali Ha'i; Side B: J-Hop, Getting Sentimental Over You (45 rpm) (Box 3)
  - Both Sides: Youth for Understanding Wind Ensemble (Box 3)
  - Album
    - Both Sides: Light Classical Vocal Music (Box 3)
    - Both Sides: Dance of the Court Dancer (Box 3)
    - Both Sides: Ohmaz Ifach-Song of Marko Melkon, Violinist Nick Doneff and Oud Darbuka (Kaliphone Turkish) (Box 3)
    - Side A: Aman Memo-Song by Karmony Garbis, Violin Nick Doneff, and Marco Melkon, Oud Darbuka (Kaliphone); Side B: Aman Karshoulauma Oyoun Song by Kamony Garbis Violin, & Oud Zill Darbuka (Kaliphone) (Box 3)
    - Side A: Melody from Orpheus Gluck; Side B: Variation #7 Brahms (Box 3)
    - Side A: Classical Music, Jar Shehnai Recital; Side B: Light Classical Music, Jar Shahnai Recital (Box 3)
    - Both Sides: Light Music of Bengal, Instrumental Trio (Box 3)